Miguel Carvalho

Lisbon, Portugal



m@miguelcarvalho.xyz



linkedin.com/in/migcarva



https://www.miguelcarvalho.xyz/

Summary

My name is Miguel Carvalho, and I'm a Frontend Engineer from Portugal, with a passion for Minimalistic Architecture, Clean Design, and Empowering Technology.

In the last 10 years, I did a successful career change, founded a startup working on SaaS for management and logistics, joined the fantastic team at Bright Pixel to help build better StayUps (contrary to startups, the former live longer), had an amazing time translating the world with Unbabel.

Since 2020 I went full on freelancing: I've helped Munii build a new way of banking, joined forces with ASAP to help speed up the research on Parkinson, created a better zoom alternative for the hybrid workplace with Around and delivery the best digital art experience with Sedition.

Experience



Senior Software Engineer - Web3

Sedition

Mar 2022 - Present (1 year)

Sedition is focused on selling the best digital art on the internet. My work with them is mostly focused on bringing web3 to the company, allowing users to mint and buy artworks with Ethereum. I'm leading the Frontend team, mentoring junior engineers and helping with recruitment to expand the team.

TypeScript - React - EtherJs - WagmiJs - Redux - Jest - EJB - SASS - HAML

Senior Software Engineer

Around by Miro Labs

Oct 2021 - Feb 2022 (5 months)

Joined Around to help the Head of Product do rapid prototyping of new ideas and test them internally.

TypeScript - React - React Native - Electron - Jest - RxJs - Styled Components - Storybook



Mentor

Feb 2021 - Oct 2021 (9 months)

Job Club is a project that was created through Tech4COVID19 with the objective of helping out in the job search process. With this goal in mind, we host several workshops, webinars and other online events.

ум Senior Product Engineer

YLD

Mar 2021 - Sep 2021 (7 months)

ASAP's mission is to foster collaboration and resources to better understand the underlying causes of Parkinson's disease. As a Senior Product Engineer, I'm using all my experience, creativity, and problem-solving skills to be the bridge between Product, Design, and Engineering.

TypeScript - React - Jest - Emotion - Recoil - Storybook - Algolia

Agile Engineer

Munii

Sep 2020 - Feb 2021 (6 months)

Munii was building a challenger bank (like Revolut or n26). I joined them as a Frontend Team Lead, with an agile approach. As a founder engineer, I defining the architecture, best practices and selecting the correct technologies for the job.

TypeScript - React - React Native - Jest - Redux - Styled Components - Storybook

M Senior Frontend Engineer

Unbabel

Sep 2019 - Aug 2020 (1 year)

I joined Unbabel in 2019, to help the Video team get the product ready for prime time. They were struggling with some key features, and with only 2 junior engineers, they needed someone who could structure the project in a scalable way, while solving some bottlenecks the team had created.

As part of Unbabel's Frontend Tribe, I was deeply committed to the development of a Proof of Concept for the next generation of Unbabel's customer interface, and we decided micro-frontends was the solution to our growing codebase. With that PoC's success, I was now overseeing the architecture for Unbabel's Customer Service Portal, while mentoring younger developers and sharing knowledge through workshops and presentations.

Typescript - Vue - Vuex - RxJs - Single SPA - Flask - SASS - Storybook



Software Engineer

Bright Pixel

Oct 2017 - Sep 2019 (2 years)

I joined Bright Pixel, in 2017, to lead the Frontend of the Bank of Portugal's new statistics portal. I was leading a team of 3 frontend engineers, which would grow to 6 by the end of the project.

This was a very complex project, and getting into the codebase business logic was not easy for newcomers. Pair programming and code reviews become part of my daily work, and I used them as a way to ensure code quality but also that every engineer was on the same level.

React - Jest - Redux - Styled Components - Storybook



Web Developer

EAE - East Atlantic Engineering

Nov 2016 - Sep 2017 (11 months)

Junior Web Developer

EAE - East Atlantic Engineering May 2016 - Nov 2016 (7 months)

🙏 Co Founder

Logisthica 2014 - 2016 (2 years)

V Consultant and Auditor

Vsa Inovação Apr 2011 - May 2013 (2 years 2 months)

Architect

Tetractys Arquitectos Sep 2008 - Jul 2011 (2 years 11 months)

Trainee Architect

Oxalis Architecture Nov 2006 - Jan 2007 (3 months)

Education

Instituto Superior Técnico

Master of Architecture (M.Arch.), Architecture 2002 - 2010

<Academia de Código_>

Bootcamp, Java, JavaScript 2016 - 2016 Intensive JAVA & JAVASCRIPT Bootcamp based in Lisbon.

Skills

JavaScript • Software Development • Project Management • React.js • Redux.js • TypeScript • Jest • Vue.js • styled-components • RxJS

Honors & Awards

3rd Place - Business Ideas Competition - Instituto Politécnico de Setúbal Jun 2015

Silver in Public Affairs - Best of Swiss Web 2017 - Best of Swiss Web 2017

Development of:

- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/fisch/ueberfischung.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/bananen/keine-krummen-bananen.html

Client: Migros-Genossenschafts-Bund, Zürich

Bronze in Marketing, Best of Swiss Web 2017 - Best of Swiss Web 2017

Development of:

- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/fisch/ueberfischung.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/bananen/keine-krummen-bananen.html

Client: Migros-Genossenschafts-Bund, Zürich

Shortlist in Mobile Web, Best of Swiss Web 2017 - Best of Swiss Web 2017

Development of:

- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/fisch/ueberfischung.html
- https://generation-m.migros.ch/de/nachhaltigkeitsthemen/bananen/keine-krummen-bananen.html

Client: Migros-Genossenschafts-Bund, Zürich